<resources>
    <string name="app_name">diary</string>
    <string name="title_activity_month_list_view">MonthListView</string>
    <string name="title_activity_write_diary">WriteDiary</string>
    <string name="title_activity_reavial">ReavialActivity</string>
    <string name="title_activity_main2">Main2Activity</string>
    <string name="title_activity_write_diary_fab">WriteDiaryFAB</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>

    <string-array name="theme1">
        <item>theme1</item>
        <item>theme2</item>
        <item>theme3</item>
        <item>theme4</item>
        <item>theme5</item>
        <item>theme6</item>


    </string-array>

    <string-array name="monthListNumber">
        <item>1月</item>
        <item>2月</item>
        <item>3月</item>
        <item>4月</item>
        <item>5月</item>
        <item>6月</item>
        <item>7月</item>
        <item>8月</item>
        <item>9月</item>
        <item>10月</item>
        <item>11月</item>
        <item>12月</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="diarybackbround">
        <item>black</item>
        <item>white</item>
    </string-array>

    <!--일기장 달마다 뜨는 문장-->
    <string-array name="monthT">
        <item>"1月 새해의 시작"</item>
        <item>"2月 너무 짧아 시간이 빨리 가지?"</item>
        <item>"3月 슬슬 봄이 올 시간"</item>
        <item>"4月 꽃들이 빼꼼 얼굴을 드러내는 시간"</item>
        <item>"5月 따스하고 즐거운 TIME"</item>
        <item>"6月 여름의 시작인지 해가 점점 강해지지?"</item>
        <item>"7月 앗, 아이스크림 생각이 점점 강해지네"</item>
        <item>"8月 아이스크림으론 무리 빙수와 바다"</item>
        <item>"9月 식욕과 잠과 책의 시간이지"</item>
        <item>"10月 푸르른 색과 붉디 붉은 색이 너무 잘 어울려"</item>
        <item>"11月 뭐했다고 벌써 시간이 이렇게 되었지?"</item>
        <item>"12月 마무리의 시간. 후회 없기를 바라"</item>
    </string-array>


    <!-- TODO: Remove or change this placeholder text -->
    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Hello blank fragment</string>
    <string name="section_format">Hello World from section: %1$d</string>
    <string name="title_activity_diary_two">DiaryTwo</string>
    <string name="title_activity_diary_part">DiaryPart</string>

    <string-array name="mots">
        <item>사랑받고 싶다면 사랑하라, 그리고 사랑스럽게 행동하라
-벤자민 프랭클린-</item>
        <item>정성과 마음을 다하고 생각이 깊은 사람일수록
상대방에게 정성과 진실한 마음을 더욱더 발견하게 된다
-톨스토이-</item>
        <item>누구도 지신이 받은 것으로 인해 존경받지 않는다
존경은 자신이 베푼 것에 대한 보답이다
-캘빈 쿨리지-</item>
        <item>가장 어두운 시간은 해뜨기 바로 직전의 시간이다
-파울로 코엘료-</item>
        <item>자기 자신을 희생하는 것처럼 행복한 일은 없다
-도스토예프스키-</item>
        <item>어제는 과거이고, 내일은 미래이고 그리고 오늘은 선물입니다
그래서 오늘은 현재(present=선물)라고 불립니다
-빌 킨-</item>
        <item>아이들에게 꾸지람보다는 좋은 본보기가 더 절실하게 필요하다
-주베르-</item>
        <item>부모란 자녀에게 사소한 어떤 것을 줘서 아이가 행복하도록 만들어주는 존재이다
-오그든 내시-</item>
        <item>나는 항상 항상 나의 밖에서 강점과 자신감을 찾았지만,
그것은 내 안에서 나오는 것이다.
그것은 항상 거기에 있다
-안나 프로이드</item>
        <item>믿음이 있는 사람에게는 어떠한 설명도 필요 없다
믿음이 없는 이에게는 어떠한 설명도 불가능하다
-토마스 아퀴나스</item>
        <item>당신이 몇 살이든, 어떤 환경에서 자랐든,
어떤 교육을 받았든, 당신의 대부분을 이루고 있는 것은
개발되지 않는 잠재력이다
-조지 레오나르드</item>
        <item>자신을 한계 짓지 말라
많은 이들이 자신이 할 수 있는 것에 대해 한계를 정한다
당신은 당신의 마음이 정하는 만큼 갈 수 있다
당신이 믿는 것, 당신은 그것을 성취할 수 있다
-메리 케이 애시</item>
        <item>지혜는 그 어떤 재산보다 더 중요하다
-소포클레스-</item>
        <item>자신에 대해 긍정적인 생각을 하는 방법은
긍정적인 행동을 하는 것이다
사람들은 생각한 대로 살지 않으면 사는 대로 생각한다
-폴 발레리-</item>
        <item>내 경험으로는 항상'그저 어린애'와 함께하는 것이 '그저 어른'과 함께하는
것보다 훨씬 더 나았기 대문에 '그저 어린애'라는 말을 문제삼을 수 밖에 없다
-프란 레보비츠-</item>
        <item>정말 위대하고 감동적인 모든 것은 자유 안에서 일할 수 있는 것들에 의해 창조된다
-알버트 아인슈타인-</item>
        <item>전쟁에서 이기기란 지진을 이기는 것과 마찬가지다
-재닛 랜킨-</item>
        <item>바로 지금 여기 앉아 아픔과 기쁨을 느끼는 우리의 신체야 말로 우리가 온전한 인간이 되고 완전히
깨어 완전히 살기 위해 필요한 바로 그것 임을 깨닫는 것 역시 도움이 된다
-페마 코드론-</item>
        <item>(기억이란)인간의 진정한 재산이다, 기억 속의 인간은 가장 부유하면서 또 가장 빈곤하다
-알렉산더 스미스-</item>
        <item>웃음은 두 사람간의 가장 가까운 거리이다
-빅터 보르게-</item>
        <item>우리는 다른 사람이 욕심을 낼 때 겁을 내려고 하고, 다른 사람이 겁을 낼 때만 욕심을 부리곤 한다
-워런 버펏-</item>
        <item>중요한 것은 사랑을 받는 것이 아니라 사랑을 하는 것이었다.
-월리엄 서머셋 모옴-</item>
        <item>한 사람이 다른 한 사람을 사랑하는 것. 이는 모든 일 중 가장 어려운 일이고, 궁극적인
최후의 시험이자 증명이며, 그 외 모든 일은 이를 위한 준비일 뿐이다.
-라이너 마리아 릴케-</item>
        <item>부자가 되려면 부자들과 어울려 살아가는 끔찍함을 견뎌야 한다
-로건 피어설 스미스-</item>
        <item>명확한 목표는 말의 곁눈 가리개처럼 목표를 가진 이의 시야를 좁게 하기 마련이다
-로버트 프로스트-</item>
    </string-array>
    <string name="title_activity_scrolling_detail_diary">ScrollingDetailDiary</string>
    <string name="large_text">
        "Material is the metaphor.\n\n"

        "A material metaphor is the unifying theory of a rationalized space and a system of motion."
        "The material is grounded in tactile reality, inspired by the study of paper and ink, yet "
        "technologically advanced and open to imagination and magic.\n"
        "Surfaces and edges of the material provide visual cues that are grounded in reality. The "
        "use of familiar tactile attributes helps users quickly understand affordances. Yet the "
        "flexibility of the material creates new affordances that supercede those in the physical "
        "world, without breaking the rules of physics.\n"
        "The fundamentals of light, surface, and movement are key to conveying how objects move, "
        "interact, and exist in space and in relation to each other. Realistic lighting shows "
        "seams, divides space, and indicates moving parts.\n\n"

        "Bold, graphic, intentional.\n\n"

        "The foundational elements of print based design typography, grids, space, scale, color, "
        "and use of imagery guide visual treatments. These elements do far more than please the "
        "eye. They create hierarchy, meaning, and focus. Deliberate color choices, edge to edge "
        "imagery, large scale typography, and intentional white space create a bold and graphic "
        "interface that immerse the user in the experience.\n"
        "An emphasis on user actions makes core functionality immediately apparent and provides "
        "waypoints for the user.\n\n"

        "Motion provides meaning.\n\n"

        "Motion respects and reinforces the user as the prime mover. Primary user actions are "
        "inflection points that initiate motion, transforming the whole design.\n"
        "All action takes place in a single environment. Objects are presented to the user without "
        "breaking the continuity of experience even as they transform and reorganize.\n"
        "Motion is meaningful and appropriate, serving to focus attention and maintain continuity. "
        "Feedback is subtle yet clear. Transitions are efﬁcient yet coherent.\n\n"

        "3D world.\n\n"

        "The material environment is a 3D space, which means all objects have x, y, and z "
        "dimensions. The z-axis is perpendicularly aligned to the plane of the display, with the "
        "positive z-axis extending towards the viewer. Every sheet of material occupies a single "
        "position along the z-axis and has a standard 1dp thickness.\n"
        "On the web, the z-axis is used for layering and not for perspective. The 3D world is "
        "emulated by manipulating the y-axis.\n\n"

        "Light and shadow.\n\n"

        "Within the material environment, virtual lights illuminate the scene. Key lights create "
        "directional shadows, while ambient light creates soft shadows from all angles.\n"
        "Shadows in the material environment are cast by these two light sources. In Android "
        "development, shadows occur when light sources are blocked by sheets of material at "
        "various positions along the z-axis. On the web, shadows are depicted by manipulating the "
        "y-axis only. The following example shows the card with a height of 6dp.\n\n"

        "Resting elevation.\n\n"

        "All material objects, regardless of size, have a resting elevation, or default elevation "
        "that does not change. If an object changes elevation, it should return to its resting "
        "elevation as soon as possible.\n\n"

        "Component elevations.\n\n"

        "The resting elevation for a component type is consistent across apps (e.g., FAB elevation "
        "does not vary from 6dp in one app to 16dp in another app).\n"
        "Components may have different resting elevations across platforms, depending on the depth "
        "of the environment (e.g., TV has a greater depth than mobile or desktop).\n\n"

        "Responsive elevation and dynamic elevation offsets.\n\n"

        "Some component types have responsive elevation, meaning they change elevation in response "
        "to user input (e.g., normal, focused, and pressed) or system events. These elevation "
        "changes are consistently implemented using dynamic elevation offsets.\n"
        "Dynamic elevation offsets are the goal elevation that a component moves towards, relative "
        "to the component’s resting state. They ensure that elevation changes are consistent "
        "across actions and component types. For example, all components that lift on press have "
        "the same elevation change relative to their resting elevation.\n"
        "Once the input event is completed or cancelled, the component will return to its resting "
        "elevation.\n\n"

        "Avoiding elevation interference.\n\n"

        "Components with responsive elevations may encounter other components as they move between "
        "their resting elevations and dynamic elevation offsets. Because material cannot pass "
        "through other material, components avoid interfering with one another any number of ways, "
        "whether on a per component basis or using the entire app layout.\n"
        "On a component level, components can move or be removed before they cause interference. "
        "For example, a floating action button (FAB) can disappear or move off screen before a "
        "user picks up a card, or it can move if a snackbar appears.\n"
        "On the layout level, design your app layout to minimize opportunities for interference. "
        "For example, position the FAB to one side of stream of a cards so the FAB won’t interfere "
        "when a user tries to pick up one of cards.\n\n"
    </string>

</resources>
